<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>CharloPL</title>
      <link>https://cryosnake22.github.io/charlopl.com</link>
      <description>My personnal website</description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://cryosnake22.github.io/charlopl.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Finding Your Passion</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://cryosnake22.github.io/charlopl.com/posts/post2/</link>
          <guid>https://cryosnake22.github.io/charlopl.com/posts/post2/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://cryosnake22.github.io/charlopl.com/posts/post2/">&lt;p&gt;Finding one’s passion feels like a never-ending journey. There’s always a shinier thing around the corner that catches your eye. And typically, even if you do find something you are deeply passionate about, there will be days when you simply do not have the motivation to get out of bed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-one-s-passion&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#finding-one-s-passion&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: finding-one-s-passion&quot;&gt;Finding one’s passion.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s okay to love many things and to be interested in lots of different subjects, even if they don’t seem like they’ll lead to a career path. I know you feel like you need money, we all do, but basing your time budget on exterior motivations is a plan for a regret-filled death.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sunk-cost-fallacy&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#sunk-cost-fallacy&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: sunk-cost-fallacy&quot;&gt;Sunk Cost Fallacy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us have already invested a considerable chunk of our time to the pursuit of a path, wether we chose it or others did for us. And to change said path is scary since it would mean you wasted all the time previously invested.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the truth is that nothing is wasted. The skills you acquired in your past will serve in the future as unlikely as that may seem. If you want to pursue some other field or passion just god damn do it. Why is it so important for you to do this ? Because:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-re-gonna-die-soon&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#you-re-gonna-die-soon&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: you-re-gonna-die-soon&quot;&gt;You’re gonna die soon.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may not seem like it but your time is very limited. As people get older they say time moves quicker, the reason why it seems that way is because they’ve let their life go by without fighting (Post to come on this).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you get older, your mind gets duller, your body starts hurting and many things you take for granted go away.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re in your 20’s you have energy so USE IT. Not on booze parties and drugs, use it to learn shit. Learn about stuff you love, learn to love learning, spend your energy on things that are actually helping you because HEED MY WORD YOU WONT HAVE IT FOR LONG. Stop looking for instant gratification and start seeking things that will earn you freedom in the long term.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;anywho&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#anywho&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: anywho&quot;&gt;Anywho&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, back to the topic of passion. If you don’t know what your passion, at least be passionate about finding your passion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. I have a problem staying on track&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Boring Stuff is Cool Actually</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://cryosnake22.github.io/charlopl.com/posts/post1/</link>
          <guid>https://cryosnake22.github.io/charlopl.com/posts/post1/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://cryosnake22.github.io/charlopl.com/posts/post1/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-s-that-possible&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#how-s-that-possible&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: how-s-that-possible&quot;&gt;How’s that possible?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve struggled a lot with this issue in the past and I think you have too.
You know you’ve got so much to do and you also know you should get started, but the thought of initiating the task makes doing the dishes seem like a vacation. I too have been stuck in procrastination hell,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But fear not for I have the solution. Here it comes: Love doing it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;crazy right ? who would’ve thought. problem solved! end of the post.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may need more explaining&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean is not that you have to love doing the dishes or that you have to love doing the math study you’ve been avoiding all week. What I mean is that you need to find a reason why doing this thing is worth your time. And I swear that you can find meaningfulness in even the most menial things in a way which will give you the motivation to go through with them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me start with an example: doing the dishes. Nobody likes doing them, the inherent act of doing the dishes is not fun. But there is a way to reframe this menial task into something that is worth your time, actually there are many ways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By doing the dishes I am training my discipline and therefore growing as a person.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By doing the dishes I am cleaning my home, taking pride in my environment.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By doing the dishes I am creating a better environment for myself and for me to accomplish my goals&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By doing the dishes I am getting rid of mental noise the will liberate my mind to focus on more important things.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could keep going and going but I think you got the idea.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here is that no matter how little the impact, no matter how little and insignificant the task, you can find something to latch on. Something which will give the task validity and importance to you. If you’re doing math homework and you don’t feel like this will bring you anything in life or you’re wondering “when will I ever use this”, you could think of things like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am practicing my problem solving muscle, which will serve me greatly in life.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am improving my discipline and focus.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything can turn into a task which you personally find important if you frame it correctly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;once-again-why-is-this-important&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#once-again-why-is-this-important&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: once-again-why-is-this-important&quot;&gt;Once again, why is this important ?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boring stuff is the stuff that will take you from where you are now and to where you want to be. Studying one day for 5 hours because you got a burst of motivation is not what gets you there. If you want to move your life in the direction you desire, what you need is unrelenting effort and actioning. What you need is consistency.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 minutes a day for a month is infinitely better than 5 hours every two weeks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stuff you’re inherently excited about should be your compass, it should guide you to where you wish to take your life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excitement is the equivalent to wanting to build a building, getting a loan, buying the land and buying the tools.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But without laying bricks one by one every day, you’re never gonna have a building, just an empty lot with nothing but unrealized dreams. And this is where the boring stuff comes in. This is where learning to love laying those 10 bricks a day really pays off.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you want to stop hoping and never achieving, you need to start doing this today. Time to fall in love with boring shit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
